Tim Wallace | Full-Stack Developer

905-861-1148 | timwallacedev@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/timothy-wallacedev | github.com/TimWallaceDev | youtube.com/@TimWallaceDev

PROFILE

With a background in jazz trombone, I bring a unique blend of creativity and technical expertise to full-stack development. I specialize in modern frameworks like React and Express, staying current with the latest technologies. In my spare time, I run a YouTube channel where I solve CSS challenges, breaking down problems and sharing my thought process. My passion for both learning and teaching drives me to continually innovate and grow as a developer.

SKILLS

HTML, CSS, SASS, Tailwind.css, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Next.js, Node.js, Express, MySQL, Git, Jest, React Testing Library, ESLint, Nginx, REST APIs, Mobile First Development, GitHub

PROJECTS

Web Developer/Designer | Melody MasterMind

ARP 2024, BRAINSTATION CAPSTONE

• Developed a full-stack music guessing game using React, Express, MySql database, authentication using JWTs, and Spotify API to present during "Demo Day". Currently deployed and self-hosted.

Web Developer | Return Relay

ARP 2024, BRAINSTATION HACKATHON

• Using figma designs from the UI/UX team, developed a working React demo with the development team to present to Shopify representatives during a 24 hour hackathon.

EDUCATION

BrainStation | Diploma, Software Engineering

JAN 2024 - APR 2024, TORONTO

University of Toronto | Bachelors of Jazz Performance, Trombone

SEP 2014 - APR 2018, TORONTO

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Web Developer

APR 2024 - PRESENT, TORONTO

- Work closely with clients to ensure timely delivery of the final product, and that the design and functionality meets the client's needs.
- Create maintainable and readable code using HTML, SASS, and React.
- Use a mobile first approach to make websites responsive at every breakpoint and screen size.
- Manage deployment to server, creating a seamless experience for the clients.

Web Developer / Designer | Human Magic

Designed and developed the entire website independently, from conceptualization to deployment.

Web Developer | Heavyweights Brass Band

 Realized the designer's vision by creating custom carousel and audio player components, enhancing the site's interactivity and user experience.

Field Representative | Mama Earth Organics

APR 2017 - JAN 2024, TORONTO

- Built strong relationships with customers to create a positive experience and leave a great impression.
- I honed my interpersonal skills, developed a solutions-oriented approach, and gained a deep understanding of the natural and organic products industry.